<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<ValueSet xmlns="http://hl7.org/fhir">
  <id value="CDAActRelationshipType"/>
  <text>
    <status value="extensions"/><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><p class="res-header-id"><b>Generated Narrative: ValueSet CDAActRelationshipType</b></p><a name="CDAActRelationshipType"> </a><a name="hcCDAActRelationshipType"> </a><ul><li>Include these codes as defined in <a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html"><code>http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActRelationshipType</code></a><span title="Version is not explicitly stated, which means it is fixed to 3.1.0, the version found through the package references"> version &#x1F4E6;3.1.0</span><table class="none"><tr><td style="white-space:nowrap"><b>Code</b></td><td><b>Display</b></td><td><b>Definition</b></td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-RSON">RSON</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has reason</td><td>**Description:** The reason or rationale for a service. A reason link is weaker than a trigger, it only suggests that some service may be or might have been a reason for some action, but not that this reason requires/required the action to be taken. Also, as opposed to the trigger, there is no strong timely relation between the reason and the action. As well as providing various types of information about the rationale for a service, the RSON act relationship is routinely used between a SBADM act and an OBS act to describe the indication for use of a medication. Child concepts may be used to describe types of indication.<br/><br/>*Discussion:* In prior releases, the code &quot;SUGG&quot; (suggests) was expressed as &quot;an inversion of the reason link.&quot; That code has been retired in favor of the inversion indicator that is an attribute of ActRelationship.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-MITGT">MITGT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">mitigates</td><td>The source act removes or lessens the occurrence or effect of the target act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-CIND">CIND</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has contra-indication</td><td>A contraindication is just a negation of a reason, i.e. it gives a condition under which the action is not to be done. Both, source and target can be any kind of service; target service is in criterion mood. How the strength of a contraindication is expressed (e.g., relative, absolute) is left as an open issue. The priorityNumber attribute could be used.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-PRCN">PRCN</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has pre-condition</td><td>A requirement to be true before a service is performed. The target can be any service in criterion mood. For multiple pre-conditions a conjunction attribute (AND, OR, XOR) is applicable.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-TRIG">TRIG</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has trigger</td><td>A pre-condition that if true should result in the source Act being executed. The target is in typically in criterion mood. When reported after the fact (i.e. the criterion has been met) it may be in Event mood. A delay between the trigger and the triggered action can be specified.<br/><br/>*Discussion:* This includes the concept of a required act for a service or financial instrument such as an insurance plan or policy. In such cases, the trigger is the occurrence of a specific condition such as coverage limits being exceeded.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-COMP">COMP</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has component</td><td>The target act is a component of the source act, with no semantics regarding composition or aggregation implied.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-ARR">ARR</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">arrival</td><td>The relationship that links to a Transportation Act (target) from another Act (source) indicating that the subject of the source Act entered into the source Act by means of the target Transportation act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-CTRLV">CTRLV</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has control variable</td><td>A relationship from an Act to a Control Variable. For example, if a Device makes an Observation, this relates the Observation to its Control Variables documenting the device's settings that influenced the observation.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-DEP">DEP</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">departure</td><td>The relationship that links to a Transportation Act (target) from another Act (source) indicating that the subject of the source Act departed from the source Act by means of the target Transportation act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OBJC">OBJC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has continuing objective</td><td>A desired state that a service action aims to maintain. E.g., keep systolic blood pressure between 90 and 110 mm Hg. Source is an intervention service. Target must be an observation in criterion mood.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OBJF">OBJF</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has final objective</td><td>A desired outcome that a service action aims to meet finally. Source is any service (typically an intervention). Target must be an observation in criterion mood.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OUTC">OUTC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has outcome</td><td>An observation that should follow or does actually follow as a result or consequence of a condition or action (sometimes called &quot;post-conditional&quot;.) Target must be an observation as a goal, risk or any criterion. For complex outcomes a conjunction attribute (AND, OR, XOR) can be used. An outcome link is often inverted to describe an outcome assessment.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-GOAL">GOAL</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has goal</td><td>A goal that one defines given a patient's health condition. Subsequently planned actions aim to meet that goal. Source is an observation or condition node, target must be an observation in goal mood.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-RISK">RISK</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has risk</td><td>A noteworthy undesired outcome of a patient's condition that is either likely enough to become an issue or is less likely but dangerous enough to be addressed.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-CHRG">CHRG</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has charge</td><td>A relationship that provides an ability to associate a financial transaction (target) as a charge to a clinical act (source). A clinical act may have a charge associated with the execution or delivery of the service.<br/><br/>The financial transaction will define the charge (bill) for delivery or performance of the service.<br/><br/>Charges and costs are distinct terms. A charge defines what is charged or billed to another organization or entity within an organization. The cost defines what it costs an organization to perform or deliver a service or product.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-COST">COST</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has cost</td><td>A relationship that provides an ability to associate a financial transaction (target) as a cost to a clinical act (source). A clinical act may have an inherit cost associated with the execution or delivery of the service.<br/><br/>The financial transaction will define the cost of delivery or performance of the service.<br/><br/>Charges and costs are distinct terms. A charge defines what is charged or billed to another organization or entity within an organization. The cost defines what it costs an organization to perform or deliver a service or product.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-CREDIT">CREDIT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has credit</td><td>A credit relationship ties a financial transaction (target) to an account (source). A credit, once applied (posted), may have either a positive or negative effect on the account balance, depending on the type of account. An asset account credit will decrease the account balance. A non-asset account credit will decrease the account balance.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-DEBIT">DEBIT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has debit</td><td>A debit relationship ties a financial transaction (target) to an account (source). A debit, once applied (posted), may have either a positive or negative effect on the account balance, depending on the type of account. An asset account debit will increase the account balance. A non-asset account debit will decrease the account balance.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SAS">SAS</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">starts after start of</td><td>The source Act starts after the start of the target Act (i.e. if we say &quot;ActOne SAS ActTwo&quot;, it means that ActOne starts after the start of ActTwo, therefore ActOne is the source and ActTwo is the target).<br/><br/>*UsageNote:* Inverse code is **SBS**</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SPRT">SPRT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has support</td><td>Used to indicate that an existing service is suggesting evidence for a new observation. The assumption of support is attributed to the same actor who asserts the observation. Source must be an observation, target may be any service (e.g., to indicate a status post).</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SPRTBND">SPRTBND</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has bounded support</td><td>A specialization of &quot;has support&quot; (SPRT), used to relate a secondary observation to a Region of Interest on a multidimensional observation, if the ROI specifies the true boundaries of the secondary observation as opposed to only marking the approximate area. For example, if the start and end of an ST elevation episode is visible in an EKG, this relation would indicate the ROI bounds the &quot;ST elevation&quot; observation -- the ROI defines the true beginning and ending of the episode. Conversely, if a ROI simply contains ST elevation, but it does not define the bounds (start and end) of the episode, the more general &quot;has support&quot; relation is used. Likewise, if a ROI on an image defines the true bounds of a &quot;1st degree burn&quot;, the relation &quot;has bounded support&quot; is used; but if the ROI only points to the approximate area of the burn, the general &quot;has support&quot; relation is used.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-PERT">PERT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has pertinent information</td><td>This is a very unspecific relationship from one item of clinical information to another. It does not judge about the role the pertinent information plays.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-AUTH">AUTH</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">authorized by</td><td>A relationship in which the target act authorizes or certifies the source act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-CAUS">CAUS</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">is etiology for</td><td>**Description:** An assertion that an act was the cause of another act.This is stronger and more specific than the support link. The source (cause) is typically an observation, but may be any act, while the target may be any act.<br/><br/>**Examples:**<br/><br/> *  a growth of Staphylococcus aureus may be considered the cause of an abscess<br/> *  contamination of the infusion bag was deemed to be the cause of the infection that the patient experienced<br/> *  lack of staff on the shift was deemed to be a supporting factor (proximal factor) causing the patient safety incident where the patient fell out of bed because the bed-sides had not been put up which caused the night patient to fall out of bed</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-COVBY">COVBY</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">covered by</td><td>A relationship in which the source act is covered by or is under the authority of a target act. A financial instrument such as an Invoice Element is covered by one or more specific instances of an Insurance Policy.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-DRIV">DRIV</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">is derived from</td><td>Associates a derived Act with its input parameters. E.G., an anion-gap observation can be associated as being derived from given sodium-, (potassium-,), chloride-, and bicarbonate-observations. The narrative content (Act.text) of a source act is wholly machine-derived from the collection of target acts.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-EXPL">EXPL</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has explanation</td><td>This is the inversion of support. Used to indicate that a given observation is explained by another observation or condition.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-ITEMSLOC">ITEMSLOC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">items located</td><td>Items located</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-LIMIT">LIMIT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">limited by</td><td>A relationship that limits or restricts the source act by the elements of the target act. For example, an authorization may be limited by a financial amount (up to $500). Target Act must be in EVN.CRIT mood.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-MFST">MFST</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">is manifestation of</td><td>An assertion that a new observation may be the manifestation of another existing observation or action. This assumption is attributed to the same actor who asserts the manifestation. This is stronger and more specific than an inverted support link. For example, an agitated appearance can be asserted to be the manifestation (effect) of a known hyperthyroxia. This expresses that one might not have realized a symptom if it would not be a common manifestation of a known condition. The target (cause) may be any service, while the source (manifestation) must be an observation.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-NAME">NAME</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">assigns name</td><td>Used to assign a &quot;name&quot; to a condition thread. Source is a condition node, target can be any service.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-PREV">PREV</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has previous instance</td><td>A relationship in which the target act is a predecessor instance to the source act. Generally each of these instances is similar, but no identical. In healthcare coverage it is used to link a claim item to a previous claim item that might have claimed for the same set of services.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-REFR">REFR</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">refers to</td><td>A relationship in which the target act is referred to by the source act. This permits a simple reference relationship that distinguishes between the referent and the referee.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-REFV">REFV</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has reference values</td><td>Reference ranges are essentially descriptors of a class of result values assumed to be &quot;normal&quot;, &quot;abnormal&quot;, or &quot;critical.&quot; Those can vary by sex, age, or any other criterion. Source and target are observations, the target is in criterion mood. This link type can act as a trigger in case of alarms being triggered by critical results.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SUBJ">SUBJ</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has subject</td><td>Relates an Act to its subject Act that the first Act is primarily concerned with.<br/><br/>Examples<br/><br/>1.  The first Act may be a ControlAct manipulating the subject Act<br/>2.  The first act is a region of interest (ROI) that defines a region within the subject Act.<br/>3.  The first act is a reporting or notification Act, that echos the subject Act for a specific new purpose.<br/><br/>Constraints<br/><br/>An Act may have multiple subject acts.<br/><br/>Rationale<br/><br/>The ActRelationshipType &quot;has subject&quot; is similar to the ParticipationType &quot;subject&quot;, Acts that primarily operate on physical subjects use the Participation, those Acts that primarily operate on other Acts (other information) use the ActRelationship.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SUMM">SUMM</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">summarized by</td><td>An act that contains summary values for a list or set of subordinate acts. For example, a summary of transactions for a particular accounting period.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-XCRPT">XCRPT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">Excerpts</td><td>The source is an excerpt from the target.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-VRXCRPT">VRXCRPT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">Excerpt verbatim</td><td>The source is a direct quote from the target.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-FLFS">FLFS</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">fulfills</td><td>The source act fulfills (in whole or in part) the target act. Source act must be in a mood equal or more actual than the target act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OCCR">OCCR</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">occurrence</td><td>The source act is a single occurrence of a repeatable target act. The source and target act can be in any mood on the &quot;completion track&quot; but the source act must be as far as or further along the track than the target act (i.e., the occurrence of an intent can be an event but not vice versa).</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OREF">OREF</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">references order</td><td>Relates either an appointment request or an appointment to the order for the service being scheduled.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SCH">SCH</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">schedules request</td><td>Associates a specific time (and associated resources) with a scheduling request or other intent.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-RPLC">RPLC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">replaces</td><td>A replacement source act replaces an existing target act. The state of the target act being replaced becomes obselete, but the act is typically still retained in the system for historical reference. The source and target must be of the same type.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SUCC">SUCC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">succeeds</td><td>**Definition:** A new act that carries forward the intention of the original act, but does not completely replace it. The status of the predecessor act must be 'completed'. The original act is the target act and the successor is the source act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-SEQL">SEQL</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">is sequel</td><td>An act relationship indicating that the source act follows the target act. The source act should in principle represent the same kind of act as the target. Source and target need not have the same mood code (mood will often differ). The target of a sequel is called antecedent. Examples for sequel relationships are: revision, transformation, derivation from a prototype (as a specialization is a derivation of a generalization), followup, realization, instantiation.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-APND">APND</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">is appendage</td><td>An addendum (source) to an existing service object (target), containing supplemental information. The addendum is itself an original service object linked to the supplemented service object. The supplemented service object remains in place and its content and status are unaltered.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-DOC">DOC</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">documents</td><td>The source act documents the target act.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-ELNK">ELNK</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">episodeLink</td><td>Expresses an association that links two instances of the same act over time, indicating that the instance are part of the same episode, e.g. linking two condition nodes for episode of illness; linking two encounters for episode of encounter.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-GEN">GEN</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has generalization</td><td>The generalization relationship can be used to express categorical knowledge about services (e.g., amilorid, triamterene, and spironolactone have the common generalization potassium sparing diuretic).</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-GEVL">GEVL</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">evaluates (goal)</td><td>A goal-evaluation links an observation (intent or actual) to a goal to indicate that the observation evaluates the goal. Given the goal and the observation, a &quot;goal distance&quot; (e.g., goal to observation) can be &quot;calculated&quot; and need not be sent explicitly.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-INST">INST</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">instantiates (master)</td><td>Used to capture the link between a potential service (&quot;master&quot; or plan) and an actual service, where the actual service instantiates the potential service. The instantiation may override the master's defaults.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-MTCH">MTCH</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">matches (trigger)</td><td>A trigger-match links an actual service (e.g., an observation or procedure that took place) with a service in criterion mood. For example if the trigger is &quot;observation of pain&quot; and pain is actually observed, and if that pain-observation caused the trigger to fire, that pain-observation can be linked with the trigger.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-OPTN">OPTN</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">has option</td><td>A relationship between a source Act that provides more detailed properties to the target Act.<br/><br/>The source act thus is a specialization of the target act, but instead of mentioning all the inherited properties it only mentions new property bindings or refinements.<br/><br/>The typical use case is to specify certain alternative variants of one kind of Act. The priorityNumber attribute is used to weigh refinements as preferred over other alternative refinements.<br/><br/>Example: several routing options for a drug are specified as one SubstanceAdministration for the general treatment with attached refinements for the various routing options.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-REV">REV</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">reverses</td><td>A relationship between a source Act that seeks to reverse or undo the action of the prior target Act.<br/><br/>Example: A posted financial transaction (e.g., a debit transaction) was applied in error and must be reversed (e.g., by a credit transaction) the credit transaction is identified as an undo (or reversal) of the prior target transaction.<br/><br/>Constraints: the &quot;completion track&quot; mood of the target Act must be equally or more &quot;actual&quot; than the source act. I.e., when the target act is EVN the source act can be EVN, or any INT. If the target act is INT, the source act can be INT.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-UPDT">UPDT</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">updates (condition)</td><td>A condition thread relationship specifically links condition nodes together to form a condition thread. The source is the new condition node and the target links to the most recent node of the existing condition thread.</td></tr><tr><td><a href="http://terminology.hl7.org/5.3.0/CodeSystem-v3-ActRelationshipType.html#v3-ActRelationshipType-XFRM">XFRM</a></td><td style="color: #cccccc">transformation</td><td>Used when the target Act is a transformation of the source Act. (For instance, used to show that a CDA document is a transformation of a DICOM SR document.)</td></tr></table></li></ul></div>
  </text>
  <url value="http://hl7.org/cda/stds/core/ValueSet/CDAActRelationshipType"/>
  <version value="2.0.1-sd-202510-matchbox-patch"/>
  <name value="CDAActRelationshipType"/>
  <title value="CDAActRelationshipType"/>
  <status value="draft"/>
  <experimental value="false"/>
  <date value="2025-10-29T22:15:57+01:00"/>
  <publisher value="Health Level 7"/>
  <contact>
    <name value="HL7 International - Structured Documents"/>
    <telecom>
      <system value="url"/>
      <value value="http://www.hl7.org/Special/committees/structure"/>
    </telecom>
    <telecom>
      <system value="email"/>
      <value value="structdog@lists.HL7.org"/>
    </telecom>
  </contact>
  <description value="A code specifying the meaning and purpose of every ActRelationship instance. Each of its values implies specific constraints to what kinds of Act objects can be related and in which way."/>
  <compose>
    <include>
      <system value="http://terminology.hl7.org/CodeSystem/v3-ActRelationshipType"/>
      <concept>
        <code value="RSON"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MITGT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CIND"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PRCN"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="TRIG"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="COMP"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ARR"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CTRLV"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DEP"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OBJC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OBJF"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OUTC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="GOAL"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="RISK"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CHRG"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="COST"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CREDIT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DEBIT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SAS"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SPRT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SPRTBND"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PERT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="AUTH"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="CAUS"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="COVBY"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DRIV"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="EXPL"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ITEMSLOC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="LIMIT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MFST"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="NAME"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="PREV"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="REFR"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="REFV"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUBJ"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUMM"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="XCRPT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="VRXCRPT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="FLFS"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OCCR"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OREF"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SCH"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="RPLC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SUCC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="SEQL"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="APND"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="DOC"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="ELNK"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="GEN"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="GEVL"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="INST"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="MTCH"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="OPTN"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="REV"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="UPDT"/>
      </concept>
      <concept>
        <code value="XFRM"/>
      </concept>
    </include>
  </compose>
</ValueSet>